

NORMAN PALISOC

Android Application Developer

My Contact

moco.palisoc@up.phinma.edu.ph

(+63-927-389-4063

Santa Barbara, Pangasinan

in norman-jay-palisoc-9bb512198

Skills and Technologies

- JAVA and Kotlin
- Jetpack Compose
- Android Jetpack
- MVVM & MVC
- Clean Architecture
- SOLID Principles
- Google Firebase & GCP
- Dagger 2 and Hilt
- · Retrofit, Volley & ION
- Work Manager
- Unit and UI Testing
- BDD (Behavior Driven Development)
- SonarQube

Education Background

PHINMA - University of Pangasinan

Bachelor of Science in Information Technology

2016 - 2020

- Awarded most outstanding information technology student from S.Y. 2018-2019 and 2019-2020.
- Won two consecutive programming competitions featuring Python and Web development.

About Me

Young, talented and professional by heart with great experience in front-end and back-end development. A competitive programmer specializing in creating android applications using JAVA, Kotlin, traditional XML design pattern and Jetpack Compose. Knowledgeable in building web applications using React and Node JS. Proactive and goal oriented with top strengths in coordinating projects and solving computer, operational and team issues.

Professional Experience

YONDU, INC. | Software Engineer - Android

October 2022 - Present

- Developed and Deployed Android Applications for S&R from scratch, and maintaining Unilab Postpaid Android Application.
- Lead the Android Team for entire Android Application Development and maintenance
- Used XML for building of UI, and Kotlin as the programming language
- Used MVVM, Clean Architecture, and SOLID principles
- Worked with Agile-Scrum methodology

Digital Space Explorer, Inc. | Android Consultant

October 2022 - Present

- Conducting application maintenance for the version two of Squadzip Android Application
- Performing bug fixes, hot fixes, and release new builds
- Coordinating with Product Management and Web/API team for API concerns and issues affecting mobile application functionalities

Digital Space Explorer, Inc. | **Android Application Developer**

February 2021 - October 2022

- Maintained, performed updates and hotfixes, and developed new features for the version 1 of the app
- Lead the Android Team for the ground up (upgrading version 1 of the android app into a new version in a new separate app)
- Used Jetpack Compose as the main foundation in creating UI
- Used MVVM architecture and properly implemented Clean Architecture and SOLID principles
- Performed Unit and UI tests
- Deployed and Maintained android applications in Google Play Console

Ingram Micro Philippines | **Information Systems Analyst**

December 2019 - March 2020

- Planned and designed system improvements to meet changing demands
- Worked with Oracle Database, informatica, and SSH Server File Manipulation using Unix Systems
- Created python scripts to properly monitor cron jobs running in the server
- Performed ETL (Extract, Transform, Load)

PHINMA - University of Pangasinan | Android Developer

June 2019 - November 2019

- Created an Android Application for recording class records in the university using JAVA and Kotlin, and XML for layout design pattern
- Collaborated with IT Faculties and University President for the changes and revisions
- Integrated API frameworks including Volley and Retrofit

Achievements

Aug. 2020

Won 1st place in the Impact Hackathon 2050 held online with over 800+ participants and 90+ submitted projects.

Jan. 2020 Best Capstone Project in Programming

Track (Class record and Attendance

monitoring system)

Best iOT Framework (Automatic Pet Feeding Machine using Arduino Micro

Controller)

Best iOT Prototype

Nov. 2019 Top 25 finalist of one of the biggest

hackathon in the world (Impact Hackathon 2050) and won as 2nd place and most viable product (MVP)

in the Baguio League

Languages

FILIPINO, ENGLISH

Certifications

NC III Visual Graphics and Design